Over the last lectures we learned a lot about nextjs,
Son derslerde, nexts'ler hakknda ok ey rendik, imdi
now there is more to learn about it
bunun hakknda daha
I will not doubt that. You can always visit the official github page I showed you a couple of times throughout
ok ey renmek var, bundan phe etmeyeceim. Bu modl boyunca size birka kez gsterdiim resmi github
this module and you can visit learnnextjs.com, an official page by the creators of nextjs
sayfasn her zaman ziyaret edebilir ve learnnextjs'i ziyaret edebilirsiniz. com, giri yapmak iin bir github hesab gerektiren
which requires a github account to log in but which then step by step walks you through the core features.
nextjs yaratclar tarafndan resmi bir sayfa ama daha sonra adm adm size temel zellikleri ile yrr.
With that, you should be able to really utilize this together with the react knowledge you gained throughout
Bununla birlikte, bu derste kazandnz tepkime bilgisiyle birlikte bunu gerekten kullanabilmeniz
this course because you are still building a react application in the end
gerekir. nk, sunucu tarafnda, ihtiyacnz olmad yerde varsaylan olarak bir
to build a react that which is server side rendered by default where you don't need to worry about
tepkime oluturmak iin bir tepki uygulamas oluturmaya devam edebilirsiniz. kod blme ve
code splitting and routing and where you therefore might have an easier time creating the react app
ynlendirme hakknda endielenmeniz ve bu nedenle oluturmay istediiniz tepki uygulamasn oluturmak iin daha
you're looking to create.
kolay bir zamannz olabilir.
Let me finish this module by showing you how you actually prepared this for deployment then. Let's quit
Bu modl, bunu datm iin nasl hazrladn gstererek bitireyim. Gelitirme sunucumuzu brakalm ve
our development server and let's revisit the package.json file.
paketi tekrar gzden geirelim. json dosyas.
Remember we added three scripts here,
Burada  komut eklediimizi hatrla,
build and start are two other scripts. Build is the script you want to execute to build the project for deployment,
ina et ve bala, dier iki senaryo. Oluturma, projeyi datm iin oluturmak istediiniz betiktir, bu
so by simply running npm run build, it will now compile and optimize all that code and spit it out,
nedenle yalnzca npm run yapsn altrarak, tm bu kodu derleyip optimize edecek ve bir sunucuya
ready for you to ship to a server.
gndermeniz iin hazr olacak ekilde tkenecektir.
Now once npm run build is done, you get the .next folder,
imdi bir kez npm run build bitti, sen olsun. Bir sonraki klasr,
this now contains all the build content.
imdi tm yap ieriini ieriyor.
Now this folder here is what actually needs to be deployed but you would deploy the entire project folder
imdi bu klasr, aslnda datlmas gereken eydir, ancak dm modllerini de
because you also need to install node modules and so on.
yklemeniz gerektiinden, tm proje klasrn databilirsiniz.
So you would deploy the entire project folder here to a host like AWS elastic beanstalk or Heroku.
Bu yzden tm proje klasrn AWS elastik beanstalk veya Heroku gibi bir sunucuya databilirsiniz.
And that's important,
Ve bu nemli,
you need a host, a service which is able to run nodeJS because nextjs
bir host, nodeJS altrmak mmkn olan bir hizmet gerekir, nk nextjs nodejs kullanr ve
uses nodejs and only works on nodejs, all the files you deploy are javascript files. So
sadece nodejs zerinde alr, konutuunuz tm dosyalar javascript dosyalardr. Yani bir nodejs hazr ana bilgisayarna
you need a nodejs
ihtiyacnz
ready host and then you ship your entire project there and just execute npm start, the third
var ve o zaman tm projenizi buraya gnderiyorsunuz ve sadece npm start, nc
script.
script'i altryorsunuz.
We can also run this locally since we got nodejs installed here.
Buraya yklediimizden beri yerel olarak da altrabiliriz.
this will now still serve the app on localhost:3000
Bu imdi, localhost: 3000 uygulamasna hizmet edecek,
but now it's the app we prepared for deployment, it works as before but it's actually using the optimized
ancak imdi datm iin hazrladmz uygulama, daha nce olduu gibi alyor ama
files where everything is minified and so on and it shows that everything works and therefore
aslnda her eyin minimize edildii ve bu ekilde her eyin ie yarad optimize
if you ship the entire project and then execute npm install followed by npm start on your server, you
edilmi dosyalar kullanyor. tm proje ve daha sonra npm install npm sunucunuzda balatmak ve sonra yrtmek
have your react nextjs application running on a real server with all the benefits nextjs
yrtmek, size nextjs verir tm avantajlar ile gerek bir sunucu zerinde alan tepki nextjs
gives you.
uygulama var.
Again if you want to learn more about nextjs,
Yine, nextjs hakknda daha fazla bilgi edinmek istiyorsanz,
don't miss the chance of diving into the official docs here on the github repo or on learnnextjs.com
github repo veya learnnextjs'deki resmi belgelere dalma ansn karmayn. com.